London Trades Council Papers on Microfilm 5215 mf
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
London Trades Council Papers on Microfilm
1860-1953
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
London Trades Council
5215 mf
1.22 cubic feet
11 microfilm reels
Minutes (administrative records), papers (documents), microfilm.
Minutes and papers of the London Trades Council.
5603555
General
Contact Information:
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives Martin P. Catherwood Library 227 Ives Hall Cornell University Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183> kheel_center@cornell.edu http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel-center
Compiled by:
Kheel Staff, May 13, 2014
EAD encoding:
Randall Miles, February 21, 2017
Biographical / Historical
The London Trades Council was a labour organisation, uniting London's trade unionists. It was founded in May 1860, it was one of four such organisations, including the Sheffield Trades Council, the Glasgow Trades Council and the Edinburgh Trades Council.
The Council helped organise labor to stand up to the employers for better working conditions.
Once the Trades Union Congress (TUC) was founded in 1868, the Labor Trades Council lost their national leadership role, but, stayed the most important trades council in the country.
By 1953 the Council had become quite radical and was re-organised by the TUC and re-founded as the London Federation of Trades Councils, which became the Greater London Association of Trades Councils (GLATC), in 1974.
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.
5603555
- The London Trades Council Minutes and Papers -- Years 1860-1882 / vol. I-IV (Reel 1)
- The London Trades Council Minutes and Papers -- Years 1883-90 -- vols. IV-VI, 1883-1890 (Reel 2)
- The London Trades Council Minutes and Papers -- Years 1891-93 -- vol. VI-VIII, 1891-1893 (Reel 3)
- The London Trades Council Minutes and Papers -- Years 1894-98 -- vol. VIII-X, 1894-1898 (Reel 4)
- The London Trades Council Minutes and Papers -- Years 1899-1909 -- vol. X-XII (Reel 5)
- The London Trades Council Minutes and Papers -- Years 1910-24 -- vol XII-XIV, 1910-1924 (Reel 6)
- The London Trades Council Minutes and Papers -- Years 1925-1938 -- vol. XIV-XVII (Reel 7)
- The London Trades Council Minutes and Papers -- Years 1939-49 -- vol. XVII-XX, 1939-1949 (Reel 8)
- The London Trades Council Minutes and Papers -- Years 1950-1953 -- vol. XXI (Reel 9)
- The London Trades Council Minutes and Papers -- Detailed Account Books & Balance Sheets -- 1860-1868, 1872-1873, 1940-1953, 1860-1953 (Reel 10)
- The London Trades Council Minutes and Papers -- Years 1861-1952 (Reel 11)